Felix Higuera

Front End Developer

Maril.com felixedmundoh@hotmail.com https://felixhiguera.website/ https://github.com/felixhiguera

in /in/felix-edmundo-higuera-alonso-8605a9ba/

Knowledgeable front end developer with experience designing and building and maintaining responsive websites and mobile apps. Proficient with CSS and JS Frameworks, with extensive knowledge of UX and user psychology. Notable achievements include boosting the conversion rate of an existing website by 30%.

Skills

FRONTEND: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React, UX/UI, Wordpress, Figma, SEO. **Technical Support:**

- Competent in installing, configuring and troubleshooting operating systems (e.g Linux, Windows).
- Capable of diagnosing and solving hardware and software faults.
- Good interpersonal and communication skills, able to work under pressure.

Languages: Spanish(native), English(advanced).

Education

2019-2020 - Higher Diploma in IT - CCT College Dublin, Ireland 2003-2007 - Bachelor of Computer Science - Mexico.

Work Experience



IT SPECIALIST | NED COLLEGE | October 2019 - Present | Dublin, Ireland

- Update landing pages on Wordpress using modern CSS techniques and Javascript.
- Perform bug fixes and code reviews.
- Collaborate closely with the team to finish web projects under a tight schedule
- Perform troubleshooting of the network caused by equipment malfunction.
- Execute preventive and corrective maintenance of computer hardware.
- Upgrade, configure and install Operative System, e.g. Linux, Windows
- Install, configure and test WiFi for the school.
- Handle hardware installation e.g. Structural cables, WIFI modem, Wireless printer, switches.



PEMEX TECHNICAL SUPPORT SPECIALIST | PEMEX (State Company) | 2015 - 2018 | Mexico

- Provided thorough IT support and problem resolution for customers.
- Performed Network Configuration e.g. Nortel Switch configuration.
- Executed preventive and corrective maintenance of computer equipment.

Projects



FelixTimes - Web

Website API about News. It requests data from API News depending of each topic for example topics like Sports, Entertainment, Business, Health.

https://felixhiguera.github.io/felixtimes/



Designo - Responsive Website

Designo website is a modern responsive website (7 page sites). It includes authentication form for email and empty inputs in the Contact page. https://felixhiguera.github.io/designo/#/



Loopstudios - Responsive Website

Loopstudios website is a modern responsive website made with HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, it was used CSS Grid for the cards and for making responsive was used Media.

https://felixhiguera.github.io/loopstudios/